(Yoo Yeon Seok)
(유연석)
(Esom)
(이솜)
(Kim Kyung Nam)
(김경남)
(Kim Mi Kyung, Jeon Seok Ho, Son Yeo Eun, Lee A Rin)
(김미경, 전석호, 손여은, 이아린)
(Choi Kwang Il, Jung Seung Gil, Yeon Je Hyung)
(최광일, 정승길, 연제형)
(Phantom Lawyer)
(유령 변호사)
(Supported by Ministry of Culture, Sports and KOCCA)
(문화체육관광부, 진흥원 지원)
(All people, places, and events in this drama are fictional.)
(본 드라마에 등장하는 인물, 장소, 사건은 모두 허구입니다.)
(Child actors filmed safely with guardians.)
(아역배우들은 보호자와 함께 안전하게 촬영했습니다.)
(All scenes involving animals were staged...)
(동물이 등장하는 장면은 모두 연출된 것이었습니다...)
(and filmed safely by welfare standards.)
(그리고 복지 기준에 따라 안전하게 촬영했습니다.)
(Episode 14)
(14화)
You're late.
늦었군요.
I feel like I just keep...
계속해서...
letting you down.
당신을 실망시킵니다.
If you're talking about standing me up, then yes.
나를 일으켜 세운다는 얘기라면 그렇습니다.
But when you get like this, I can't even be mad.
그런데 이렇게 되면 화를 낼 수가 없어요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
I have a favour to ask.
부탁드릴 게 있어요.
I'd like you to stay away from the office for a while.
당분간 사무실에 나오지 않았으면 좋겠습니다.
And please, don't ask why.
그리고 제발, 이유는 묻지 마세요.
I'm really sorry...
정말 죄송해요...
for bailing on our plans today.
오늘 우리 계획을 취소하기 위해.
(Pit-a-Pat Butcher Restaurant)
(Pit-a-Pat 정육점 레스토랑)
Did Yi Rang not come home last night?
랑이는 어젯밤에 집에 안 들어왔나요?
- Yes, it looks that way. - I wonder if a new ghost showed up.
- 네, 그런 것 같아요. - 새로운 귀신이 나타났는지 궁금하네요.
A new ghost?
새로운 유령?
I haven't been to the office recently because of filming,
최근 촬영 때문에 사무실에 못 갔는데
so I was wondering.
그래서 궁금했어요.
But don't worry too much. I'll swing by later.
하지만 너무 걱정하지 마세요. 나중에 들르겠습니다.
Anyway, would you like a cup of tea?
어쨌든, 차 한 잔 드실래요?
(- You reek of a criminal. - A ghost took your dad.)
(- 범죄자 냄새가 나네요. - 유령이 아버지를 데려갔습니다.)
(Shin Yi Rang's dad is a criminal!)
(신이랑 아빠는 범인이다!)
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Do you not have a home? Or...
집이 없나요? 아니면...
were you kicked out?
쫓겨났어?
What's it to you?
당신에게 무슨 상관이 있나요?
You were tossing and turning all night, breaking out in a cold sweat.
당신은 밤새도록 뒤척이고 식은땀을 흘리고 있었습니다.
I was worried something was wrong.
뭔가 잘못됐다고 걱정했어요.
Did it ever occur to you that it might be your fault?
그것이 당신의 잘못일 수도 있다는 생각을 해 본 적이 있나요?
What do you mean by that?
그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
How can I get a good night's sleep with a ghost staring me down?
유령이 나를 내려다보는 상황에서 어떻게 하면 잠을 잘 수 있을까요?
Now that you get it, please just leave.
이제 알았으니 그냥 나가주세요.
I don't care where.
나는 어디든 상관하지 않습니다.
Just get out of my sight.
그냥 내 눈에서 사라지세요.
If it's not too much to ask,
너무 많은 질문이 아니라면
may I know the reason?
이유를 알 수 있을까요?
Because I find it unacceptable.
왜냐하면 나는 그것이 용납될 수 없다고 생각하기 때문입니다.
If a lawyer can't accept his client, how can he do his job?
변호사가 의뢰인을 받아들일 수 없다면 어떻게 업무를 수행할 수 있겠습니까?
Lawyer...
변호사...
Client?
고객?
By any chance, do you know who I am?
혹시, 내가 누군지 아세요?
How would I know?
내가 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Let's just say I find your face unacceptable.
그냥 당신의 얼굴이 용납될 수 없다고 생각한다고 가정해 봅시다.
It's not right to judge people by their appearance.
사람을 겉모습으로 판단하는 것은 옳지 않습니다.
Especially a legal professional,
특히 법률 전문가라면,
who must guard against prejudice and bias...
편견과 편견을 경계해야 하는 사람...
and treat everyone with fairness and justice, without discrimination.
모든 사람을 차별 없이 공정하고 정의롭게 대합니다.
And you did what you did, knowing all of that?
그리고 당신은 그 모든 것을 알고 당신이 한 일을 했습니까?
"Knowing all of that."
"그건 다 알아요."
Why would he tell me not to come in?
그 사람은 왜 나한테 들어오지 말라고 했을까?
Is he uncomfortable around me?
그 사람이 내 주변에 불편해 하는 걸까?
(Submit Yoon Jae Uk's files to the court.)
(윤재욱의 파일을 법원에 제출하세요.)
(Attorney Shin Yi Rang)
(신이랑 변호사)
Yi Rang.
이랑.
I'm calling because the files for Yoon Jae Uk's case are due today.
윤재욱 사건 파일이 오늘 마감이라 전화 드렸습니다.
I didn't get a chance to tell you,
당신에게 말할 기회가 없었어요
but about that case...
하지만 그 사건에 대해서는...
We're not handling it anymore.
우리는 더 이상 그것을 처리하지 않습니다.
What?
무엇?
Why?
왜?
Did a new ghost show up or something?
새로운 유령이 나타났다던가?
Look, Na Hyun.
봐봐 나현아.
I'm kind of in the middle of something right now.
나는 지금 뭔가를 하고 있는 중이에요.
Fine.
괜찮은.
What's his deal?
그의 거래는 무엇입니까?
The courthouse...
법원...
is really close by.
정말 가까워요.
Must be convenient for you, working so close.
너무 가까이서 일하니 편할 것 같아요.
Why now?
왜 지금?
- What do you mean? - I said, why now of all times?
- 무슨 뜻이에요? - 내가 말했지, 맨날 왜 지금이지?
Do you know what I've been through because of you?
너 때문에 내가 어떤 일을 겪었는지 알아?
My bad.
내 잘못이야.
Were you with a client?
고객과 함께 있었나요?
It's nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
Anyway, are you hungry?
어쨌든, 배고픈가요?
Mother packed us some gimbap.
엄마가 김밥을 싸주셨어요.
Hey, where did Ms. Han go?
저기, 한씨는 어디 갔나요?
Mom's gimbap?
엄마 김밥?
Smells so good.
냄새가 너무 좋아요.
Here, have a bite. Try it.
자, 한 입 먹어보세요. 시도해 보세요.
- You want some, Honey? - Yes.
- 좀 드실래요, 여보? - 예.
Sa Rang, you open up too.
사랑아 너도 마음을 열어라
Honey, your egg gimbap is out of this world.
여보, 계란김밥은 이 세상 것이 아니에요.
- It really is. - Hey, hold on. Wait a second.
- 정말이에요. - 잠깐만요. 잠깐만요.
- I'm not hungry, so I'll eat later. - What?
- 배고프지 않으니 나중에 먹겠습니다. - 무엇?
And if by any chance I get possessed,
그리고 혹시 내가 홀린 경우
throw water on me right away, okay?
당장 나한테 물 좀 줘, 알았지?
Don't hesitate and don't hold back, okay?
주저하지 말고 참지 마세요, 알았죠?
Okay, goodness. I got it. Don't worry.
알았어, 맙소사. 알겠어요. 괜찮아요.
Oh, right. Your mom's been really worried.
아, 그렇죠. 너희 엄마가 정말 걱정하셨구나.
You know, whether you're eating and sleeping properly.
제대로 먹고 자고 있는지 알잖아요.
You know how parents are, always worrying about their kids.
부모님들이 어떤 마음인지 아시겠지만, 항상 자녀에 대해 걱정하고 계십니다.
Hey...
안녕...
The thing is...
문제는...
What is it? Is something on your mind?
그것은 무엇입니까? 뭔가 마음에 걸리는 게 있나요?
You can tell me. You know my lips are sealed.
당신은 나에게 말할 수 있습니다. 내 입술이 봉인되어 있다는 걸 당신도 알잖아요.
I guess not?
아닌 것 같은데?
All right. Anyway, since we're talking about her,
괜찮은. 어쨌든, 그녀에 대해 이야기하고 있으니
you should call your mom.
엄마한테 전화해야 해.
- She's been worried sick all morning. - Okay, I will.
- 그녀는 아침 내내 걱정이 많았어요. - 알았어, 그럴게.
Gosh, I skipped breakfast so we could eat together.
맙소사, 같이 먹으려고 아침을 거른 거야.
This amazing smell is impossible to resist.
이 놀라운 냄새는 거부할 수 없습니다.
Pardon the intrusion.
침입을 용서하십시오.
I'm not usually so impertinent,
난 평소에 그렇게 무례한 편은 아닌데,
but I find this aroma simply irresistible.
하지만 나는 이 향이 참을 수 없을 것 같다고 생각합니다.
If it wouldn't be too much of an imposition,
너무 부담스럽지 않다면
may I have just a little, a tiny little taste?
조금만, 아주 조금만 맛봐도 될까요?
Yes, yes! Of course!
예, 그렇습니다! 물론!
I'm the general manager here.
제가 이곳의 총책임자입니다.
- Thank you, Mr. General Manager. - Please, have a seat.
- 감사합니다, 총지배인님. - 자리에 앉으세요.
Water.
물.
They say a well-fed ghost is a happy ghost.
배불리 먹는 귀신이 행복한 귀신이라고 하잖아요.
I guess I should let him eat before I snap him out of it.
내가 그를 쫓아내기 전에 그가 먹도록 해야 할 것 같아요.
Here, have some of this water too.
여기 이 물도 좀 드세요.
This is incredible. Goodness. How can something taste this good?
정말 놀랍습니다. 선량. 어쩜 이렇게 맛있을 수가 있지?
Is it really that good?
정말 그렇게 좋은가요?
It's truly delicious.
정말 맛있어요.
How should I put it?
어떻게 넣어야 할까요?
It's somehow...
왠지...
The kind of taste that tugs at your heartstrings.
심금을 울리는 그런 맛.
My mother-in-law's cooking is to die for...
시어머니의 요리는 정말 끝내주네요...
No, I mean, it's incredible.
아니, 내 말은, 정말 믿을 수 없다는 거야.
- Please, eat up. - Yes, I'd love to.
- 식사하세요. - 네, 그러고 싶습니다.
There's soup too.
수프도 있어요.
Prosecutor Kim, I wanted to ask you something.
김 검사님, 묻고 싶은 게 있습니다.
Do you know why Yoon Jae Uk switched lawyers?
윤재욱이 변호사를 바꾼 이유를 아시나요?
Since you're the prosecutor on his case,
당신이 그 사건의 검사이니까
I figured you might have heard something.
나는 당신이 뭔가를 들었을 것이라고 생각했습니다.
I haven't heard anything official, but I have a hunch.
공식적인 소식은 듣지 못했지만 예감이 듭니다.
There was a case 20 years ago involving his father, Yoon Dae Myeong.
20년 전, 아버지 윤대명과 관련된 사건이 ​​있었다.
And the prosecutor on that case was Shin Gi Jung.
그리고 그 사건의 검사는 신기정이었다.
Lawyer Shin's father.
신 변호사의 아버지.
Seriously?
진지하게?
And?
그리고?
- I'm home. - You're back.
- 집에 왔어요. - 돌아왔구나.
So...
그럼...
How's Yi Rang doing?
이랑은 잘 지내요?
He's fine, and it turns out a new ghost really did show up.
그는 괜찮습니다. 그리고 새로운 유령이 실제로 나타났습니다.
But it seems like Yi Rang and that ghost don't get along.
그런데 이랑과 그 귀신은 사이가 좋지 않은 것 같다.
He told me to wake him up right away if he gets possessed.
혹시 빙의되면 바로 깨우라고 하더군요.
Why? What's the ghost like?
왜? 유령은 어떤가요?
Yi Rang said it's a woman in her 60s,
랑이가 60대 여성이라고 하더군요,
but when he was possessed, he definitely sounded like a man.
하지만 그가 빙의되었을 때는 확실히 남자처럼 들렸습니다.
You must have heard wrong.
당신은 잘못 들었나봐요.
But Yi Rang said something strange to the ghost.
그런데 랑이가 귀신에게 이상한 말을 했다.
- Like what? - Something like, "Because of you, I..."
- 어떤가요? - "너 때문에 내가..." 같은 말
But his tone... How should I put it?
그런데 그의 말투는... 어떻게 표현해야 할까요?
It sounded resentful.
분개한 것 같았다.
(Butcher's restaurant)
(정육점)
This lunch box... Did Yi Rang eat it?
이 도시락...이랑이 먹었나요?
Yes. Wait, no. The possessed Yi Rang did.
예. 잠깐, 아니. 빙의된 랑이 그랬다.
Tell me more about that ghost.
그 유령에 대해 좀 더 말해주세요.
The ghost?
유령?
He said the egg gimbap was absolutely delicious.
계란김밥이 정말 맛있다고 하더군요.
- What else? - What else?
- 또 뭐야? - 또 뭐야?
He was very polite, and he spoke in a very refined way.
그는 매우 예의 바르고, 매우 세련된 방식으로 말했습니다.
But why are you asking?
그런데 왜 묻는 걸까요?
- It's nothing. - I'm going to get the shop ready.
- 아무것도 아니야. - 가게 준비를 할게요.
Okay.
좋아요.
I told Bong Soo to wake me up right away if I get possessed. Seriously.
봉수한테 빙의되면 바로 깨워달라고 했어요. 진지하게.
How long have you been living like this?
언제부터 이렇게 살아왔나요?
- What? - How many ghosts...
- 무엇? - 유령이 몇 명이나...
- have you encountered? - Why are you asking?
- 만난 적 있어요? - 왜 묻는 거죠?
It just seems like it must have been so hard for you.
너도 많이 힘들었을 것 같은데.
Depending on the ghost, it could've been dangerous.
유령에 따라서는 위험할 수도 있었습니다.
It was. I've almost gotten into accidents...
그랬다. 사고날 뻔했어요...
- and almost died. - And you still kept doing it?
-거의 죽을 뻔 했어요. - 그런데도 계속 그랬어요?
They come day and night begging for help. How could I just stop?
그들은 밤낮으로 도움을 구걸하며 찾아옵니다. 어떻게 그냥 멈출 수 있겠어요?
Lawyer Shin.
신 변호사.
You're a good person.
당신은 좋은 사람이에요.
More like a total pushover.
완전한 푸시 오버와 비슷합니다.
That's why...
그렇기 때문에...
I'm meeting with you like this right now.
나는 지금 이렇게 당신을 만나고 있습니다.
But from now on,
하지만 지금부터
I'm going to be more cold-hearted.
나는 더욱 냉담해질 것이다.
So...
그럼...
Are you drawn to any of these talismans in particular?
특히 이 부적 중 어떤 것에 끌리시나요?
A talisman I'm drawn to...
내가 끌리는 부적...
Yes, Father.
네, 아버지.
I'm calling because there's a ghost I need to send on.
보내야 할 유령이 있어서 전화했어요.
No, it has to be today.
아니요, 오늘이어야 합니다.
If you're busy, I'll come to you.
바쁘시면 제가 찾아갈게요.
Since you won't leave even when I tell you to,
내가 떠나라고 해도 넌 떠나지 않을 테니까
I have no choice but to send you on myself.
나는 당신을 직접 보내는 것 외에는 선택의 여지가 없습니다.
So you've decided to send me on?
그래서 나를 보내기로 결정하셨나요?
Yes. That's the plan.
예. 그게 계획이에요.
You seem to resent me a great deal.
당신은 나를 몹시 원망하는 것 같습니다.
But other than the fact that I'm dead,
하지만 내가 죽었다는 사실 외에
I have no idea who I am,
나는 내가 누구인지 전혀 모른다
so I can neither repent nor apologise.
그래서 나는 회개할 수도, 사과할 수도 없습니다.
Has this happened before?
전에도 이런 일이 있었나요?
A ghost you sent on without telling them who they were.
당신이 누구인지 말하지 않고 보낸 유령.
Was I really that bad of a person?
내가 정말 그렇게 나쁜 사람이었나?
Was I so vile that you won't even tell me who I was?
내가 누구인지조차 말해주지 않을 정도로 내가 너무 사악했나요?
Prosecutor Shin Gi Jung...
신기정 검사...
used my father as a scapegoat.
아버지를 희생양으로 이용했어요.
For his own gain,
자신의 이익을 위해
he drove my father...
그 사람이 내 아버지를 몰았어...
to his death.
그의 죽음까지.
Yes.
예.
You're someone who can never be forgiven.
당신은 절대로 용서받을 수 없는 사람입니다.
You deceived the people who trusted you,
당신은 당신을 믿었던 사람들을 속였습니다.
framed an innocent man, and destroyed his family.
무고한 사람을 모함하고 그의 가족을 파괴했습니다.
A man died because of you,
너 때문에 한 남자가 죽었어
and the ones who survived...
그리고 살아남은 사람들은...
have suffered for a very long time.
아주 오랫동안 고생하셨습니다.
And after committing such a shameless act,
그리고 그런 뻔뻔한 행동을 저지른 후,
you just died without ever apologising.
넌 사과도 없이 그냥 죽었어.
The fact that I didn't tell you who you were...
당신이 누구인지 말하지 않았다는 사실은...
You should be grateful for that.
당신은 그것에 대해 감사해야합니다.
Because if you had known,
만약 당신이 알고 있었다면,
the pain would've made you want to die all over again.
그 고통은 당신을 다시 죽고 싶게 만들었을 것입니다.
No!
아니요!
Blocked you!
당신을 차단했습니다!
I just can't seem to beat my son at games anymore.
나는 더 이상 게임에서 내 아들을 이길 수 없는 것 같습니다.
- But you can't beat Dad in a race. - What?
- 하지만 경주에서는 아빠를 이길 수 없어요. - 무엇?
A race to home. Ready, set, go!
집으로 가는 경주. 준비, 설정, 출발!
Dad, that's not fair.
아빠, 그건 불공평해요.
(Seoin Elementary School)
(서인초등학교)
(Happy, Joyful, and Friendly, Just Like Yesterday!)
(어제처럼 행복하고 즐겁고 다정해요!)
Yi Rang, look.
이랑아, 봐라.
For a fastball, you take your index and middle fingers...
패스트볼의 경우 검지와 중지를 사용합니다...
and put them together like this.
그리고 이렇게 모아보세요.
Then you throw it like you're pushing it forward.
그런 다음 앞으로 밀듯이 던집니다.
The middle finger.
가운데 손가락.
- Like this? - That's it.
- 이와 같이? - 그게 다야.
Want to try throwing one?
한번 던져볼까?
But Dad...
하지만 아빠는...
I'm not so sure I can do it.
나는 그것을 할 수 있을지 확신하지 못한다.
When you feel that way, take a deep breath.
그런 느낌이 들 때, 심호흡을 해보세요.
Tell yourself, "I can do this."
스스로에게 "난 할 수 있어"라고 말해보세요.
Believing it will give you real courage.
그것을 믿으면 진정한 용기가 생길 것입니다.
I can do this.
나는 이것을 할 수 있다.
All right.
괜찮은.
Not bad.
나쁘지 않아요.
It was a little off target, but I could really see the spin on it.
약간 목표에서 벗어났지만 실제로 회전하는 모습을 볼 수 있었습니다.
Great job, Yi Rang.
수고했어요, 랑이랑.
One more.
하나 더.
Why did you do it back then?
그땐 왜 그랬어요?
- What? - The man I remember...
- 무엇? - 내가 기억하는 그 사람...
Who on earth was he?
도대체 그는 누구였습니까?
You left on your own terms,
당신은 당신 뜻대로 떠났어요,
so why are you showing up again on your own terms?
그런데 왜 당신 뜻대로 다시 나타나는 겁니까?
You're someone I've been trying so hard to forget.
당신은 내가 잊기 위해 열심히 노력한 사람입니다.
Don't come to me with that clueless look...
그런 멍한 표정으로 다가오지 마세요...
on your face.
당신의 얼굴에.
All right, I'll stop.
알았어, 그만할게.
I won't try to find out who I was anymore.
나는 더 이상 내가 누구인지 알아내려고 노력하지 않을 것이다.
To be honest, it's a little hard for me to accept.
솔직히 말해서 좀 받아들이기 힘들죠.
I may not know who I am or have any memories,
내가 누구인지 모르거나 기억이 없을 수도 있어요,
but the idea that I lived that kind of life...
그런데 내가 그런 삶을 살았다는 생각은...
I guess that was hard for me to accept.
저로서는 받아들이기 힘들었던 것 같아요.
That's why I was so desperate to know what my life was like.
그래서 나는 내 삶이 어떤 것인지 알고 싶어 그토록 필사적이었습니다.
But now...
하지만 지금은...
I'll believe you.
나는 당신을 믿을 것입니다.
You...
당신은...
really are...
정말...
a truly good person.
정말 좋은 사람.
Thanks to you, I had someone to talk to,
덕분에 얘기 나눌 사람이 생겼어요
and right now, you're struggling with whether...
그리고 지금 당신은...
sending me away is the right thing to do.
나를 보내는 것이 옳은 일이다.
Whatever you decide, it's okay.
무엇을 결정하든 괜찮습니다.
For showing up so suddenly out of the blue,
갑자기 나타나서
I'm truly sorry.
정말 죄송해요.
Don't hold this against me.
나에 대해 이것을 비난하지 마십시오.
(Pit-a-Pat Butcher Restaurant)
(Pit-a-Pat 정육점 레스토랑)
Mom, I'm home.
엄마, 나 집에 왔어요.
What about the ghost?
유령은 어떻습니까?
What?
무엇?
I mean...
내 말은...
Bong Soo said you had a new ghost.
봉수씨가 새로운 유령이 생겼다고 하더군요.
Well...
음...
He's gone.
그는 사라졌습니다.
- Gone? - Yes.
- 다 쓴? - 예.
He wanted to leave,
그는 떠나고 싶어했어요
so I just let him go.
그래서 나는 그를 그냥 보내주었다.
I see.
알겠어요.
Mom.
엄마.
I didn't sleep very well last night.
어젯밤에 잠을 잘 못 잤어요.
- Okay, then. Go get some rest. - Okay.
- 그럼요. 가서 좀 쉬세요. - 좋아요.
Thank you for your time.
시간을 내주셔서 감사합니다.
Just a few days ago,
불과 며칠 전,
you didn't know Attorney Shin Yi Rang's father...
신이랑 변호사 아버지를 모르셨군요...
was Prosecutor Shin Gi Jung.
신기정 검사였습니다.
How did you find that out?
그걸 어떻게 알아냈나요?
I got a text from an unknown number.
모르는 번호로 문자가 왔습니다.
The lawyer must be here.
변호사가 여기 있어야 해요.
(Blocked number: Do not trust Shin Yi Rang.)
(차단번호 : 신이랑을 믿지 마세요.)
(His father drove your father to death.)
(그의 아버지가 당신의 아버지를 죽음으로 몰아넣었습니다.)
(He's the corrupt prosecutor, Shin Gi Jung.)
(그는 부패한 검사 신기정이다.)
It all ended over 20 years ago anyway.
어쨌든 모든 것은 20년 전에 끝났습니다.
I don't want to dwell on it anymore.
나는 더 이상 그것에 대해 생각하고 싶지 않습니다.
I've read the articles from that time.
그때의 기사를 읽었습니다.
And it said you refused to accept that your father's death...
그리고 당신은 아버지의 죽음을 받아들이기를 거부했다고 하더군요...
was a suicide.
자살이었습니다.
My father always used to say...
우리 아버지는 항상 이렇게 말씀하시곤 했어요...
that people must take responsibility for their actions.
사람들은 자신의 행동에 책임을 져야 한다는 것입니다.
And he lived his entire life by those words.
그리고 그는 평생을 그 말씀대로 살았습니다.
A man like that committing suicide?
그런 사람이 자살을 했다고?
It's unthinkable.
그것은 상상도 할 수 없는 일이다.
Do you still have the case files from back then?
그때 사건 파일 아직도 가지고 있나요?
Yes.
예.
But what's the point now? It's been 22 years.
하지만 지금 요점은 무엇입니까? 22년이 지났습니다.
That's exactly why.
그것이 바로 그 이유입니다.
It may be late,
늦을 수도 있어요
but don't you think we should uncover the truth?
하지만 우리가 진실을 밝혀야 한다고 생각하지 않나요?
Why are you so invested in this case?
이 사건에 왜 그렇게 투자하셨나요?
You couldn't even grieve properly when you lost a family member,
가족을 잃었을 때 제대로 슬퍼하지도 못하고,
and I know what that feels like.
그게 어떤 느낌인지 알아요.
There's someone in my life who's just like that.
내 인생에도 꼭 그런 사람이 있다.
(Pit-a-Pat Butcher Restaurant)
(Pit-a-Pat 정육점 레스토랑)
- Why aren't you in bed? - I just can't sleep.
- 왜 침대에 안 누워 있어요? - 잠이 안 와요.
Why aren't you asleep, Mom?
엄마 왜 안 자요?
Me? I'm just prepping for work tomorrow.
나? 저는 내일 출근 준비만 하고 있어요.
Why?
왜?
Is there something you want to talk about?
얘기하고 싶은 게 있나요?
No.
아니요.
Mom, why did you never leave Seocho-dong?
엄마, 왜 한 번도 서초동을 떠나지 않으셨나요?
It's full of people who bad-mouthed Dad around here.
이 주변에는 아빠를 욕하는 사람들이 가득해요.
Why you'd insist on running your business here...
왜 여기서 사업을 운영하겠다고 고집하시는지...
I've always wondered.
나는 항상 궁금했다.
I thought if I left this place,
이곳을 떠나면
it would mean that I was admitting defeat.
그것은 내가 패배를 인정했다는 뜻일 것이다.
I refused to accept that your father was a bad person.
나는 네 아버지가 나쁜 사람이라는 사실을 받아들이기를 거부했다.
I believed the truth would come out someday.
언젠가는 진실이 밝혀질 것이라고 믿었습니다.
I felt I had to hold on until then.
그때까지 버텨야겠다는 생각이 들었어요.
So, all this time...
그래서 그동안...
You've believed in Dad this whole time.
당신은 그동안 아빠를 믿었어요.
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
But that's just how I feel.
하지만 내 기분은 딱 그래요.
Even if you feel differently than I do,
당신이 나와 다르게 느끼더라도
I understand and respect that.
나는 그 점을 이해하고 존중합니다.
(Specialising in domestic meat)
(국내산 고기 전문)
(Shin Yi Rang Law Office)
(신이랑 법률사무소)
(Attorney Shin Yi Rang)
(신이랑 변호사)
Na Hyun.
나현.
This is about your father, isn't it?
이건 네 아버지에 관한 얘기야, 그렇지?
How did you know?
어떻게 알았나요?
I found out from Prosecutor Kim...
김검사한테서 알아낸건데...
that your father was involved...
네 아버지가 연루됐다고...
in Mr. Yoon's father's case.
윤 씨 아버지의 경우다.
I also met with Yoon Jae Uk and heard his side of the story.
윤재욱씨도 만나서 그의 이야기를 들어봤습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
For digging into it without telling you.
말하지 않고 파고들었으니까.
No, don't be.
아니, 그러지 마세요.
It's my fault for not being open with you.
당신에게 마음을 열지 못한 건 내 잘못이에요.
I should have told you sooner.
더 일찍 말했어야 했는데.
Yi Rang, to me...
랑이, 나한테는...
I mean...
내 말은...
You don't have to try so hard.
그렇게 열심히 노력할 필요는 없습니다.
Later, when you're more comfortable, you can tell me then.
나중에 편해지면 그때 말해도 돼요.
Just one thing, though.
하지만 한 가지만요.
Just let me be there for you.
내가 당신을 위해 거기에 있게 해주세요.
What with my sister's case and all,
내 여동생 사건이니 뭐니는 어쩌고,
I really owe you so much.
나는 정말로 당신에게 너무 많은 빚을 지고 있습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I'll never forget this.
나는 이것을 결코 잊지 않을 것입니다.
Okay, that's enough. You're going to spoil me.
알았어, 충분해. 당신은 나를 망치게 될 것입니다.
I want to keep that promise.
나는 그 약속을 지키고 싶다.
So please, let me.
그러니 제발 허락해주세요.
Chairman, Attorney Shin Yi Rang is here.
신이랑 변호사님이 오셨습니다.
He doesn't have an appointment, but he said you'd see him if I told you.
그 사람은 약속이 없는데 내가 말하면 만나겠다고 하더군요.
Send him in.
그를 보내세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
I'm here to ask you...
나는 당신에게 물어보려고 왔습니다...
about my father.
내 아버지에 대해서.
Your father?
당신의 아버지?
Until now, I never tried to find out about my father.
지금까지 나는 아버지에 대해 알아내려고 한 적이 없습니다.
There were times I was curious,
궁금할 때도 있었는데,
but I always tried to push those feelings away.
하지만 나는 항상 그런 감정을 밀어내려고 노력했어요.
But now,
하지만 지금은
I want to know.
나는 알고 싶다.
The more I look at you, the more I see your father in you.
내가 당신을 더 많이 볼수록 당신에게서 당신의 아버지를 더 많이 볼 수 있습니다.
Do I?
나도요?
That tough, unwavering look in your eyes...
그 강인하고 흔들림 없는 눈빛...
It's so much like Gi Jung's.
기정이와 너무 비슷해요.
I tried to look into Gi Jung's cases, but it wasn't easy.
기정이의 사건을 알아보려고 했지만 쉽지 않았다.
I had already left the Prosecution by then,
나는 그때쯤 이미 검찰을 떠났다.
and prosecutors hostile to Gi Jung refused to cooperate at all.
기정에게 적대적인 검사들은 일절 협조를 거부했다.
However...
하지만...
There was one old case that came to mind.
예전에 생각나는 사건이 하나 있었습니다.
It was back when your father was at the Incheon Prosecutors' Office.
네 아버지가 인천검찰청에 있을 때의 일이다.
We used to meet up sometimes and just talk about life,
우리는 가끔 만나서 인생에 대해 이야기를 나누곤 했는데요,
but that day, he seemed different somehow.
그런데 그날 그 사람은 뭔가 다른 것 같았어요.
Byung Il.
병일.
Yes?
예?
It's nothing...
아무것도 아니야...
What? You can't just start and then stop. What is it? Tell me.
무엇? 그냥 시작했다가 멈출 수는 없습니다. 그것은 무엇입니까? 말해 주세요.
I don't know if this is the right thing to do.
이것이 옳은 일인지 모르겠습니다.
All I have to do is right a wrong. It should be that simple.
내가 해야 할 일은 잘못된 것을 바로잡는 것뿐입니다. 그렇게 간단해야합니다.
But for some reason,
하지만 어떤 이유에서인지
I have a bad feeling about this.
나는 이것에 대해 나쁜 느낌을 가지고 있습니다.
Hey, Gi Jung. It'll all blow over. Okay?
안녕하세요, 기정님. 모든 것이 터질 것입니다. 좋아요?
Don't dwell on it. Just forget about it.
그것에 대해 생각하지 마십시오. 그냥 잊어 버리세요.
About when was that?
그게 언제쯤이었나요?
It must've been right before the crackdown on the gangs in Chinatown.
차이나타운 갱단 단속 직전이었을 겁니다.
Chinatown...
차이나타운...
My father was found dead in a back alley in Incheon's Chinatown.
아버지는 인천 차이나타운 뒷골목에서 숨진 채 발견됐다.
- What's wrong? - I need to go to the Prosecutors' Office.
- 무슨 일이야? - 검찰청에 가야 해요.
It's been 20 years. What could you find at the prosecutor's office?
20년이 지났습니다. 검찰청에서 무엇을 찾을 수 있습니까?
There's probably no one left who even remembers Gi Jung.
아마도 기정이를 기억하는 사람은 아무도 없을 것이다.
Besides...
게다가...
Even if someone does remember him...
누군가 그를 기억하더라도...
It'll be even harder to get them to cooperate.
협력을 이끌어내는 것은 더욱 어려울 것입니다.
The police might be a different story, though.
하지만 경찰이라면 이야기가 다를 수도 있다.
The police?
경찰?
There's an Officer Choi Dong Man.
최동만 경관이 있습니다.
He's a detective who worked in Chinatown for a long time.
차이나타운에서 오랫동안 근무한 형사입니다.
He's bound to know something.
그 사람은 분명 뭔가를 알고 있을 거예요.
Detective Choi Dong Man...
최동만 형사...
Okay. Thank you, Chairman.
좋아요. 감사합니다, 의장님.
About Gi Jung...
기정에 대해서...
He was my junior, and I cared for him a great deal.
그 사람은 내 후배였고, 나는 그 사람을 매우 많이 보살폈습니다.
If you find anything new,
새로운 것을 발견하면
make sure you let me know.
꼭 알려주세요.
Yes, I will.
네, 그럴게요.
About Gi Jung...
기정에 대해서...
He was my junior, and I cared for him a great deal.
그 사람은 내 후배였고, 나는 그 사람을 매우 많이 보살폈습니다.
If you find anything new,
새로운 것을 발견하면
make sure you let me know.
꼭 알려주세요.
- Yes, sir. - Where are you? I need to see you.
- 네, 선생님. - 어디세요? 꼭 만나야 해요.
You mean right now?
지금 당장 말이에요?
Please help me.
도와주세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
And make it quick.
그리고 빨리 하세요.
(Yang Do Kyung)
(양도경)
So, what if...
그럼 만약에...
the ghost left the Okcheon Building without recovering its memories,
유령은 기억을 되찾지 못한 채 옥천빌딩을 떠났고,
where do you think it would've gone?
그게 어디로 갔을 것 같아?
A ghost that hasn't recovered its memories...
기억을 되찾지 못한 유령...
and where it might go?
어디로 갈 수 있나요?
From my experience with ghosts,
유령에 대한 내 경험에 따르면,
their favourite food, songs,
그들이 가장 좋아하는 음식, 노래,
or a loved one elicited a strong reaction.
또는 사랑하는 사람이 강한 반응을 이끌어 냈습니다.
In that case, couldn't a specific place...
그렇다면 특정 장소를 지정할 수는 없습니다...
- have the same kind of pull? - A specific place?
- 같은 종류의 당김이 있나요? - 특정 장소요?
Yes. Not by the mind,
예. 마음이 아니라,
but a place that the heart remembers,
하지만 마음이 기억하는 곳은
(Wolmido Island, 1984)
(월미도, 1984)
Just a little... Just a little more.
조금만... 조금만 더.
What? Mom, where are you going?
무엇? 엄마, 어디 가세요?
I just have somewhere to be.
난 그냥 있을 곳이 있어요.
- Okay. Take care. - Okay.
- 좋아요. 잘 지내세요. - 좋아요.
So, have you found the shaman?
그럼, 무당을 찾으셨나요?
With a little more time, I'm sure I can find him.
시간이 조금만 더 지나면 그를 찾을 수 있을 거라고 확신해요.
You know as well as I do, Director Choi,
당신도 나만큼 잘 알고 있지, 최 감독
that my father is a man of far too few words.
내 아버지는 말이 너무 적은 사람이라는 걸.
Even so, you can't do things this way.
그렇더라도 이런 식으로는 일을 할 수 없습니다.
Are you lecturing me right now?
지금 나한테 강의하고 있는 거야?
And you don't even realise the danger you're in.
그리고 당신은 자신이 처한 위험을 깨닫지도 못합니다.
It turns out my father didn't return because he was fully recovered.
알고 보니 아버지는 완치되셨기 때문에 돌아오지 않으셨습니다.
(Davith Medical Center)
(데이빗 메디컬 센터)
In this situation, what do you think you should be doing, Director Choi?
이런 상황에서 최 감독은 어떻게 해야 한다고 생각하시나요?
Whose orders should you follow if you want to make it out alive?
살아서 탈출하려면 누구의 명령을 따라야 합니까?
(Taebaek)
(태백)
What is it that you want?
당신이 원하는 것이 무엇입니까?
What my father knows, and how much he knows.
아버지는 무엇을 알고 계시고, 얼마나 알고 계시나요?
Tell me everything, from the very beginning.
처음부터 모든 것을 말해주세요.
It all began when attorney Han Na Hyun lost the case to Shin Yi Rang.
모든 것은 한나현 변호사가 신이랑에게 패소하면서 시작됐다.
Hey, you punk! Are you out of your mind?
이봐, 이 새끼야! 정신이 나갔나요?
You're acting like a damn lunatic because you're blind, is that it?
당신은 눈이 멀었기 때문에 미친놈처럼 행동하는군요, 그렇죠?
As things continued to happen that could only be explained by ghosts,
귀신으로만 설명할 수 있는 일들이 계속해서 일어나자
the Chairman started keeping a close watch on Shin Yi Rang.
회장은 신이랑을 면밀히 감시하기 시작했습니다.
So he knew from the beginning that Shin Yi Rang could see ghosts?
그럼 신이랑이 귀신을 볼 수 있다는 걸 처음부터 알고 있었던 걸까요?
Is that a good enough reason to stop treatment and return to Korea?
그게 치료를 중단하고 한국으로 돌아가야 할 충분한 이유가 되나요?
At first, the Chairman...
처음에는 회장님...
just thought of Shin Yi Rang as an eccentric.
그냥 신이랑이 괴짜라고 생각했어요.
But then, when he found out that Shin Yi Rang was Shin Gi Jung's son,
그러다가 신이랑이 신기정의 아들이라는 사실을 알게 되자
he immediately returned to Korea.
그는 곧바로 한국으로 돌아갔다.
He was worried that Shin Yi Rang might encounter Shin Gi Jung's ghost,
신이랑이 신기정의 유령을 만날까봐 걱정이 되었는데,
and that's why he came back?
그래서 그 사람이 돌아온 거야?
Yes, that's correct.
네, 맞습니다.
(Seoin Kendo Academy)
(서인검도학원)
You little...
너 꼬마...
Feeling good after taking me down?
나를 쓰러뜨리고 나면 기분이 좋아지나요?
Why does Father care about Shin Gi Jung? He's dead.
아버지는 왜 신기정을 걱정하시나요? 그는 죽었어.
I'm afraid I don't know that.
나는 그것을 모른다.
And then?
그런 다음?
After returning to Korea,
한국으로 돌아온 후
the Chairman ordered me to find the missing shaman.
회장님은 나에게 실종된 무당을 찾으라고 명령하셨다.
A shaman?
무당?
So, did you find him?
그래서 그를 찾았나요?
I asked you. Did you find the shaman?
나는 당신에게 물었다. 샤먼을 찾았나요?
I heard my father used to work at the Incheon Prosecutors' Office.
아버지가 예전에 인천검찰청에 근무하셨다고 들었습니다.
And he investigated cases related to Chinatown.
그리고 차이나타운과 관련된 사건을 조사했다.
It sounds like you'll get the full story about your father soon.
곧 아버지에 대한 전체 이야기를 듣게 될 것 같습니다.
First, I'm going to meet a detective...
먼저 탐정을 만나러 갑니다...
who might know something about his case.
그의 사건에 대해 뭔가 알고 있을지도 모르는 사람.
I know that couldn't have been easy.
그게 쉽지 않았을 거라 생각해요.
Thanks for calling.
전화해 주셔서 감사합니다.
You told me not to be alone.
혼자 있지 말라고 했잖아요.
- Gi Jung. Enough with the pictures. - Kyung Hwa.
- 기정. 사진으로 충분합니다. -경화.
- Yes? - When I look through the lens,
- 예? - 렌즈를 통해 보면
you look so much prettier that I just can't stop.
당신이 너무 예뻐서 멈출 수가 없어요.
Just a little longer. Just a few more.
조금만 더. 몇 가지만 더 말씀드리겠습니다.
My gosh.
맙소사.
- A little to your left. To the left. - My left?
- 조금 왼쪽에 있어요. 왼쪽으로. - 내 왼쪽?
- Yes, just a little to the left. - Okay.
- 네, 조금 왼쪽이에요. - 좋아요.
Hold on. From there, just a little bit back. Back.
기다리다. 거기에서 조금 돌아갑니다. 뒤쪽에.
Back. It's cold! So cold!
뒤쪽에. 춥다! 너무 추워요!
No, no.
아니, 아니.
Gi Jung, you did that on purpose, didn't you?
기정아, 일부러 그랬지?
- No, I... - You did it on purpose. You just wait.
- 아니, 난... - 일부러 그러셨잖아요. 그냥 기다리세요.
- No, I swear! No, I didn't! - Come here. Get over here.
- 아니, 맹세해요! 아니요, 그렇지 않았습니다! - 이리 오세요. 여기로 와.
- No, I didn't... - Get over here! Come on.
- 아니, 난... - 이리로 와! 어서 해봐요.
I didn't do it on...
내가 한 건 아닌데...
There was so much I wanted to say to you.
나는 당신에게 말하고 싶은 것이 너무 많았습니다.
But still...
하지만 여전히...
I'm glad you came.
당신이 와줘서 기뻐요.
What is this place?
이 장소는 무엇입니까?
Please, let me go.
제발, 저를 보내주세요.
I've told you everything I know!
나는 내가 아는 모든 것을 당신에게 말했습니다!
Officer Choi retired last year and moved back to his hometown.
최 경관은 지난해 퇴임하고 고향으로 돌아왔다.
He did?
그랬나요?
There is someone who would know a lot about Saryonghoe.
사룡회에 대해 많이 아시는 분이 계실 겁니다.
- Who? - There's this old-timer in Chinatown.
- WHO? - 차이나타운에 이런 노인이 있어요.
(Honggwan)
(홍관)
Saryonghoe?
사룡회?
Yes. I heard they were a gang...
예. 갱단이라고 들었는데...
that preyed on this area about 20 years ago.
약 20년 전에 이 지역을 먹이로 삼았던 것입니다.
Why are you looking for a bunch of thugs who disappeared ages ago?
오래 전에 사라진 깡패 무리를 왜 찾는 걸까요?
It has to do with my family.
그것은 우리 가족과 관련이 있습니다.
Please, I need your help.
제발, 당신의 도움이 필요해요.
Well, it's the same old story.
글쎄, 그것은 똑같은 오래된 이야기입니다.
They were a bunch of leeches who bled every merchant here dry.
그들은 여기 있는 모든 상인의 피를 말끔히 빨아들이는 거머리 떼였습니다.
They'd demand half our sales in exchange for "protection."
그들은 "보호"의 대가로 우리 매출의 절반을 요구할 것입니다.
If you refused, they'd trash your place.
당신이 거절하면 그들은 당신의 집을 쓰레기로 만들 것입니다.
They'd file fake complaints to ruin your business.
그들은 당신의 사업을 망치기 위해 가짜 불만을 제기할 것입니다.
They were absolutely vicious.
그들은 정말 사악했습니다.
Like vipers.
독사처럼.
Then how did a gang like that just disappear?
그렇다면 어떻게 그런 갱단이 사라졌는가?
Because one day, he showed up.
어느 날 그 사람이 나타났거든요.
A righteous and meticulous prosecutor.
정의롭고 세심한 검사.
- Let's take them all in. - Hey! Get off!
- 모두 가져가자. - 이봐요! 내리세요!
- Let go of me! - The bribes those scumbags offered...
- 날 놔줘! - 그 쓰레기들이 제공한 뇌물...
actually turned into a poison that came back to bite them.
실제로 그들을 물기 위해 되돌아오는 독으로 변했습니다.
He was that upright and sharp.
그 사람은 그만큼 꼿꼿하고 날카로웠어요.
Thanks to him, we could finally breathe again.
그 덕분에 우리는 마침내 다시 숨을 쉴 수 있게 됐다.
To us, he was a true hero.
우리에게 그는 진정한 영웅이었습니다.
I know it was a long time ago,
오래 전 일이라는 걸 알아요,
but do you happen to remember his name?
그런데 혹시 그 사람 이름 기억나나요?
I used to know it. Gosh, what was his name?
나는 그것을 알고 있었다. 맙소사, 그 사람 이름이 뭐더라?
- Maybe it was Prosecutor Shin Gi Jung? - Shin Gi Jung?
- 어쩌면 신기정 검사였나? - 신기정?
Don't you dare mention that jerk. He was nothing but a thief.
감히 그 멍청이에 대해 언급하지 마세요. 그는 도둑에 지나지 않았습니다.
That jerk was a corrupt prosecutor...
그 멍청이는 부패한 검사였어...
in bed with Saryonghoe for his own gain.
자신의 이익을 위해 사룡회와 동침한다.
No, he doesn't even deserve to be called a prosecutor.
아니, 그 사람은 검사라 불릴 자격도 없습니다.
The man was a gangster himself, the worst of the bunch.
그 남자는 갱스터 중 최악의 갱스터였습니다.
- Good to see you, sir! - Good to see you, sir!
- 만나서 반가워요, 선생님! - 만나서 반가워요, 선생님!
All right.
괜찮은.
Try to dress a little more presentably.
좀 더 멋지게 옷을 입으십시오.
And you, you punk. What's with all the flashy gold?
그리고 너, 너 펑크. 그 화려한 금은 다 뭐죠?
Goodness.
선량.
Why would you load up so much?
왜 그렇게 많이 짐을 싣겠습니까?
Two cakes? Here, you have one. Have one.
케이크 두 개? 여기 하나 있습니다. 하나 드세요.
Thank you, sir.
감사합니다.
Even the police walked on eggshells around Shin Gi Jung.
심지어 경찰도 신기정 주변을 달걀껍질 위를 걸었다.
And with his protection, the Saryonghoe just got bigger and bigger.
그리고 그의 보호로 사룡회는 점점 더 커졌다.
That's why all the merchants around here...
그래서 이 근처 상인들이 다...
The very mention of Shin Gi Jung's name makes their blood boil.
신기정의 이름만 언급되는 것만으로도 피가 끓는다.
That's how vile that jerk was. Gosh.
그 멍청이가 얼마나 사악한지. 이런.
Goodness.
선량.
That righteous prosecutor's name was...
그 정의로운 검사의 이름은...
I said my wrist hurts.
손목이 아프다고 하더군요.
It was Prosecutor Yang Byung Il.
양병일 검사였습니다.
I've told you everything I know.
나는 내가 아는 모든 것을 당신에게 말했습니다.
Please, just let me go now. Please?
제발, 지금은 그냥 보내주세요. 제발?
Just one more thing.
한 가지만 더요.
How do you get rid of a ghost?
유령을 어떻게 없애나요?
You burn it.
당신은 그것을 태워.
Burn the talisman, and the ghost disappears.
부적을 태우면 유령이 사라집니다.
Does the chairman know this?
회장님은 이 사실을 알고 계시나요?
Well? Does he?
잘? 그래요?
Yes, he's aware.
예, 그는 알고 있습니다.
Shin Yi Rang paid a visit.
신이랑님이 방문하셨습니다.
- So? - I handled it as you instructed.
- 그래서? - 지시하신 대로 처리했습니다.
Good work.
잘했어요.
(Pit-a-Pat Butcher Restaurant)
(Pit-a-Pat 정육점 레스토랑)
Thanks for being here with me today.
오늘 나와 함께 해주셔서 감사합니다.
You must be tired. Get some rest.
피곤하시겠군요. 좀 쉬세요.
You get some rest too, Yi Rang.
이랑 너도 좀 쉬어라.
(Dunggulge Supermarket)
(둥굴게 슈퍼마켓)
(Mari Stationery)
(마리 문구류)
- The best! - Looking good! Go, Seoin Elementary!
- 최고! - 좋아 보여요! 가라, 서인초등학교!
- Let's go! - Let's go!
- 갑시다! - 갑시다!
- Seoin! Seoin! - Eunho, let's go!
- 서인! 서인! - 은호야, 가자!
- Go, Eunho! - Go, Eunho!
- 가라, 은호! - 가라, 은호!
- Go, Seoin! - Go, Seoin!
- 가라, 서인아! - 가라, 서인아!
(Throw it for your dream!)
(당신의 꿈을 위해 던져보세요!)
(The Unbeatable Seoin Elementary School Baseball Team)
(무적의 서인초등학교 야구부)
- Let's go, let's go! - Let's go!
- 가자, 가자! - 갑시다!
What's wrong? You hurt your shoulder?
무슨 일이야? 어깨를 다쳤나요?
Yes.
예.
It hurts too much. I don't think I can pitch.
너무 아파요. 나는 투구를 할 수 없을 것 같아요.
Shin Yi Rang, you're up!
신이랑, 일어났구나!
Me?
나?
Yes, you! Hurry!
응, 너! 서두르다!
I can't. I...
나는 할 수 없다. 나는...
Dad.
아빠.
What are you waiting for? The coach is calling you.
당신은 무엇을 기다리고 있습니까? 코치가 당신을 부르고 있습니다.
We'll lose because of me.
나 때문에 우리가 지는 거야.
No one believes in me.
아무도 나를 믿지 않습니다.
I can't do it.
나는 그것을 할 수 없습니다.
Give me that.
그거 주세요.
They say as long as...
그들은...
you have one person in this world who believes in you,
이 세상에 당신을 믿는 사람이 한 명 있어요,
you can overcome any hardship.
어떤 어려움도 이겨낼 수 있습니다.
Even if everyone else in the world doesn't believe in you,
세상 모든 사람이 당신을 믿지 않더라도
that one person is enough to give you courage.
그 한 사람이면 용기를 낼 수 있어요.
I'm that person for you, Yi Rang. The one who'll always believe in you.
이랑 너한테는 내가 바로 그 사람이야. 언제나 당신을 믿어줄 사람.
Okay, Dad.
알았어, 아빠.
I'll try.
노력하겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
- Go, Seoin! - Go, Seoin!
- 가라, 서인아! - 가라, 서인아!
I can do this.
나는 이것을 할 수 있다.
Strike! Out!
스트라이크! 밖으로!
Yes!
예!
(Victory Roar! Seoin Wave Riders!)
(승리의 포효! 서인 웨이브 라이더스!)
Lawyer Shin? What are you doing here?
신 변호사? 여기서 뭐하는거야?
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I'm not sure myself.
나 자신도 잘 모르겠습니다.
I was just walking, and my feet must have led me here.
그냥 걷고 있었는데 내 발이 나를 여기로 이끌었나 봐요.
The talisman...
부적...
Why haven't you burned it yet?
왜 아직 태우지 않았나요?
I'm not sure myself.
나 자신도 잘 모르겠습니다.
I guess I was looking for the tiniest excuse...
가장 작은 핑계를 찾고 있었던 것 같아요...
not to burn it.
태우지 말라고.
But...
하지만...
the more I hear from people,
사람들의 이야기를 더 많이 들을수록
the more disappointed I became.
그럴수록 나는 더 실망했다.
But I'm done looking for excuses like that.
하지만 그런 핑계를 찾는 건 이제 끝났어요.
More than what anyone else says.
다른 사람이 말하는 것보다 더.
I'm going to trust what I know,
나는 내가 아는 것을 믿을 것이다
the man I've seen for myself.
내가 직접 본 그 남자.
I'm going to trust my own judgment.
나는 내 자신의 판단을 믿을 것이다.
Born in 1963.
1963년생.
August 15.
8월 15일.
Shin Gi Jung.
신기정.
You are...
당신은...
my father.
내 아버지.
(Phantom Lawyer)
(유령 변호사)
Why are you so worried about Shin Gi Jung? He died 20 years ago.
신기정씨를 왜 그렇게 걱정하시나요? 그는 20년 전에 사망했습니다.
He's the chairman of Taebaek, a major law firm.
그는 대형 로펌인 태백의 회장이다.
- He and I were like brothers. - You have to be careful.
- 그 사람과 나는 형제 같았어요. - 조심해야 해요.
- Don't worry. - It's not him.
- 괜찮아요. - 그 사람이 아니야.
- A Saryonghoe member? - Her name is Han Na Hyun.
- 사룡회 회원이요? - 이름은 한나현이에요.
Whatever you're doing, stop it right now.
무슨 일을 하든 지금 당장 멈추세요.
I can't put my son in danger just to clear my name.
단지 내 누명을 벗기 위해 내 아들을 위험에 빠뜨릴 수는 없습니다.
- Burn the talisman, the ghost vanishes. - What are your orders?
- 부적을 불태우면 유령이 사라진다. - 당신의 명령은 무엇입니까?
- Okay, I get it. Just stop. - No, Yi Rang.
- 알았어, 알겠어. 그냥 멈춰라. - 아니, 이랑.
I can't let you go like this, Dad.
이대로 놔둘 수는 없어요, 아빠.